INSTRUCTOR: Hello, everyone,
and welcome to the video for how
to create an EC2 instance with
built-in VS Code web clients,
React, React Native, and
Expo app running on it,
with a Django backend.
Let's get into it.
So once you're in
AWS, you're going
to want to launch
a new instance.
I'm just going to
call mine vscode_test.
Oop.
There we go.
Choose Ubuntu,
because all the bash
scripts that I'm going
to use are Ubuntu,
and the ones you're
going to use are Ubuntu.
I'm going to not use a T2 micro.
That's a little bit not
quite enough memory.
I've tried it on a T2 small.
That seems to be fine.
But I'm going to be
a T2 medium to make
sure it's got plenty of memory.
It's $0.05 per hour, so
if you're working on it
and then shutting it down,
it'll still be really cheap.
And even if you
do want to launch,
this as a beta, $0.05 per
hour for a whole month
works out to be
about $36 a month.
And again, this will have
your back end, your front end,
and your SQLite database on it.
So for $36 a month,
you actually get a lot.
But if you're in dev mode still
and you want to keep it cheap,
just shut down your server
when you're not using it.
I'm going to it a launch there.
I'm going to proceed
without a key pair
because my primary method
of logging into the server
is going to be through
VS Code web client.
So I don't need a key pair to
launch from PuTTY or anything.
I'm going to connect
to my instance
to start running some
scripts and hit Connect.
And that'll take a
second to connect
while the server is coming up.
So while that's doing that, I'm
going to go ahead and open up
a few ports so I can connect
to the server from my laptop,
or if it's a beta for
an app you're building,
you can give the
URL to your friends.
So to open up the ports
you need, go to Instances,
and then I clicked on--
I'll do that again.
I did it quick.
Click on the EC2
instance that you want.
Again, mine was-- there
it is-- vscode_test.
Scroll down, you'll
see Security.
The Security tab is
where you open up ports.
Security group, click on that.
And then you're going to do Edit
inbound rules for your ports.
I'm going to add
three more rules.
Custom TCP connection, I'm going
to open up port 8000 for Django.
I'm going to open up port
8080 for VS Code web client.
And I'm going to open up port
8081 for the React Native app.
I'm going to save
the-- oop, open it up
for the world on that one.
Save the rules.
Now the servers open up,
and we should be connected.
And we have a brand-new server.
So let's start putting
stuff on here now.
So the co-instructor, Elijah, we
have a bunch of scripts and apps
on there for you.
So if you go to github.com
and go to Manodiestra,
that's Elijah's GitHub username.
Go to Repositories and
then go to EC2 scripts.
This is going to be
all the scripts you
want to download everything.
And then I'm going to grab the
URL there so I can clone it.
So copy the URL for that repo,
go back here, do a git clone,
and then paste in that repo.
And there you go.
One more thing you need to do
before you start running things
is change the mode.
So the command is chmod,
and do a -R. That'll do it
for all the scripts at once.
And then the folder is EC2.
Oop.
Let me double check there.
Yeah, we've got EC2.
Yep, that looks
good, chmod - R EC2.
What do we got there?
Invalid mode.
Oh, pardon me.
Duh.
Do chmod - R775.
I've got to give
the mode, of course.
775, that'll make it
open for you, your group,
and lock down for
execution for the world.
So run that.
That looks good.
Now we're going to run
dot slash EC2 scripts,
and we're going to do
VS Code server install.
So that is now loading
all the libraries
to run VS Code on the server.
So you can code
directly on your server.
Similar to AWS
Cloud9 how it works,
but since that's been end
of lifed, VS Code web client
is a better IDE anyway.
And you can run it right on
the server just like Cloud9.
So that takes about 15 minutes.
I'm going to go ahead
and pause the video.
And I'll come back in
once the script is done.
See you in a minute.
We're back.
And that actually only
took three or four minutes
to load all that.
So that's good.
So now I'm going to open
up VS Code web client.
And actually, the
script gives you the URL
you can open right here.
So I'm going to grab that.
By the way you could
keep running scripts
inside that command line.
But I like doing
it within VS Code
because it actually has
some built-in tools to see,
oh, you're running an app,
and it'll give you the links
to view it, which I like.
So I'm going to go
straight to VS Code.
When you connect here, you need
to verify their certificate.
Maybe you've seen this
before on other websites.
But hit Advance and
then do proceed to it.
That'll accept the certificate.
And then you need to log in.
So the default
password is "changeme!"
And you can see the
file right there.
Change the password in that file
and then lock the permissions
down.
And then you'll be secure.
So now we are logged
in to the VS Code web
client running on our EC2.
I'm going to hit, "Yes,
I trust the authors,"
and open up a terminal.
Now we've got a terminal
on our VS Code web client.
I'm going to-- let's
take a look at--
let me zoom in a little
bit so you can see better.
There we go.
Look at the script here.
So we just ran vs code server
install in the other window.
Now we're going to
run install tools.
Oh.
That'll load everything
you need to run
Django and React and
React Native Expo,
and I think Python
virtual environments, too.
So that'll take a minute.
I won't pause the video,
though, because it
should be pretty quick.
You guys know any jokes,
while that's running?
Cruising along there,
about halfway done.
Once we've got
install tools done,
we'll go ahead and run
install Elijah demos,
and that'll bring in
Django, and it actually
bring in the GitHub repos with
some pre-built projects for you
guys to get started with.
Oh, well, I thought
we were done.
There we go.
So that's done now.
Now we're going to run--
there we go--
install Elijah demos.
Essentially, that'll
pull the GitHub repos
for the Django app
we're going to give you
and the React,
React Native, Expo
app we're going to give you.
So run that.
And you can see what just
popped in right there,
the Django example fall 2024,
for our back end right there.
And again, the
other script install
tools, that loaded everything
you need to run Django.
So you should be
good to go right now.
So there it is.
If you see your app is running.
So this is actually
your Django backend.
It's only what Django serves up.
It's not your beautiful front
end, it's just your back end.
So that's running.
And now it's starting
up Expo as well.
Recall that React is
the web front end.
React Native is your mobile app.
And Expo partnered
with React Native
so that you can use one
code base for all three.
It's pretty awesome.
One code base gets
you a full web app,
a full mobile app on Android
and on iOS all at once,
which is really nice.
That's fired up right there.
You can see, open and
browser, although the Expo
app is on 8081.
I found that to be finicky when
you click on that link here.
So what I'm actually going
to do, if you see up here,
I'm going to grab this
or go in here to this.
This is the link for
that Django back end.
So just switch that to 8081.
And actually, you don't
want proxy there either.
So go to the IP
address and then 8081.
Oop.
"Not found."
Hang on, let me
double check that.
Expo-- let's try this guy.
I think that should do it.
It's loading, because the first
time you log into your React app
from the web, not just
from one browser, anytime--
the first time it's
logged in period.
No, didn't like that either.
It'll load all of
your web components.
You'll see them
compile right there.
That doesn't look right.
Let me go back here, grab
the right IP address.
Let me go back to
Instances, vscode_test.
There we go.
I'm going to grab the public
IP address right here.
And then that guy, I'm going to
put 8081 and remove the S. Expo
app's not secure
yet, so remove the S.
And let's see that's
loading there.
And if you go, you
can go see it load.
There we go.
That looks good.
So you can go see it.
In your terminal,
when it's loading,
you'll see these web
components compiling.
That only happens once.
So it's lazy loading.
So everything that
needs to be compiled
is done once the first time.
So you can see that in the log.
That looks good.
While that's
compiling, you'll just
see the website
hanging and waiting.
That's normal.
That looks like it's good.
Here it is.
And we can test
it out right here.
I'm going to do Add user form
because this will save down
to your database.
Django comes with a
built-in SQLite database.
So it's a file-based
database, but it still
gives you tables and
can easily store tables
with a few million rows each.
Anything bigger
than that, you're
probably going to want to set
up a proper RDS database in AWS.
But while you're
in beta and just
building things out and vetting
out some things, SQLite is fine.
And then hit Submit,
come back here to Home.
And there it is.
There's our user
entry that we added.
So that's been persisted
to the back end.
And you're done.
Now from here, you can build it.
Go build your front end,
build your back end,
go build your app,
and build your dreams.
So just to recap,
new server, don't
forget to chmod, the directory,
so you can run those scripts.
Let's get the scripts
from Elijah's repo.
Run the vs code install.
That gets you VS Code.
Open up a terminal,
run the install tools,
and install Elijah's demos.
That gets you your
back end, which
has your database built-in,
your front end, React,
React Native, Expo.
And you can run it, take a
look, play around with it,
and start building it
out and doing more.
That is it.
Thanks for watching.
Have a good one.